John Sayles invites you to return to the scene of the crime.
Lone Star is a drama, mystery, romance film directed by John Sayles.
When the skeleton of his murdered predecessor is found, Sheriff Sam Deeds
unearths many other long-buried secrets in his Texas border town.
Sam Deeds, played by Chris Cooper.
Pilar Cruz, played by Elizabeth Peña.
Charlie Wade, played by Kris Kristofferson.
Hollis Pogue, played by Clifton James.
Mercedes Cruz, played by Miriam Colon.
Otis Payne, played by Ron Canada.
Lone Star is a 1996 American neo-Western mystery film
written, edited, and directed by John Sayles.
Set in a small town in South Texas, the film deals with a sheriff's (played by Chris Cooper)
investigation into the murder of one of his predecessors (Kris Kristofferson) decades earlier.
The cast also stars Joe Morton, Elizabeth Peña, Clifton James, Ron
Canada, Frances McDormand and Matthew McConaughey.
The film premiered at the 1996 South by Southwest Festival and received widespread critical acclaim, with critics
regarding it as a high point of 1990s independent cinema as well as one of Sayles's best films.
Sayles's screenplay was nominated for an Academy Award,
BAFTA Award, and Golden Globe Award.
The film was also nominated for four Independent Spirit Awards,
with Elizabeth Peña winning Best Supporting Female.
Lone Star was recognized by the American Film Institute in AFI's 10
Top 10 list in 2008 as a nominated Western Film.
The film explores themes of sheriff, texas, family
secrets, neo-western, dark secret.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.